之前我们已经学到了如何用限定符
By taking the knowledge that we learned about overriding resources
修饰资源文件夹
in other folders,
这次我会教你如何用代码实现平板的双页视图显示
we'll walk through the code together on how to build up the two-pane tablet UI.
首先将values-w820dp文件夹删除  因为我们还不需要
First remove the values W820dp folder because we don't need to provide
为屏幕尺寸比820dp还大的设备做适配
specific logic where the current orientation is greater than 820dp.
然后修改xml文件
Then go ahead and make the layout XML changes.
创建一个新的文件夹  命名为layout-sw600dp
Then create a new layout SW 600dp folder.
在其中创建一个新的xml文件  命名为activity_main
And then add a new file called activity_main.
它和默认layout文件夹中的activity_main.xml同名
We use the same file name as in the base layout folder activity_main so
这样  在不同尺寸的设备上就会加载对应的activity_main.xml
that this one overrides the behavior specifically on tablets.
想要看到这一部分的代码  请在gist上查找
To see the code for this file you can check out the gist below.
在这里有一个水平方向的LinearLayout作父布局
Essentially it's a horizontal linear layout that can hold a forecast fragment
在父布局内forecast fragment居左显示  detail fragment居右显示
on the left and a detail fragment on the right.
是时候来对比一下静态Fragment和动态Fragment了
Now's a good time to talk about static verses dynamic fragments.
我们实现左边的forecast fragment是静态的
In our implementation the forecast fragment is the static fragment because
因为我们在xml布局文件中已经完成了定义
we're defining it in the XML layout no matter what orientation or device size
不管设备屏幕的方向怎样  尺寸大小如何  在main activity中我们都需要forecast fragment
we know that we're going to need a forecast fragment in the main activity.
再看这边  我们只声明了一个用于放置detail fragment的容器
On the other hand, we only declare a container for the detail fragment, but
并未真正在里面实现fragment
not the actual fragment.
因为每次都要用不同的参数动态加载它
It's initialized with different arguments each time as a dynamic
所以最好在main activity的Java代码中动态完成创建
fragment, so it's better to dynamically create and add that
并在一个fragment事务中加载出来
fragment in a fragment transaction in the main activity Java code.
这样FragmentManager就可以一直掌控与动态加载有关的参数
That way the fragment manager can keep track of those initialization arguments
当设备切成横屏时  就可以将detail fragment显示出来
and pass those back to us on, after device rotation.
接下来我们需要更新一下单页布局文件
Then we need to update the one pane UI layouts so
让其和双页布局保持一致
that they're consistent with the two pane case.
在默认layout文件夹中的activity_main.xml中
So in the activity main file for the base layout folder this used to be
这里面放了一个FrameLayout  我们用来声明forecast fragment
a frame layout we're going to declare it as a forecast fragment.
这样一来就可以和双面板的布局中
That way it will match the two pane UI,
forecast fragment的声明保持一致
where this also is declared as a fragment in the XML.
之后main activity再去动态加载forecast fragment时
That way the main activity never has to worry about dynamically adding
就不必再担心会有问题发生了
the forecast fragment.
在MainActivity.java的onCreate方法中
In the main activity on create view method.
既然forecast fragment已经在xml文件中声明过了
Since the fragment is already inside this layout we can just remove this so
没必要再动态加载一遍  这一部分java代码也就不需要了
we don't dynamically add it again.
同样地  我们修改了默认layout文件夹中的activity_detail.xml
Similarly we modify the activity detail layout in the base layout folder
将FrameLayout的android:id属性改为weather_detail_container
we change the frame layout ID to be weather detail container.
这样就能和双页布局中包含detail fragment的容器id保持一致
So that it matches the container view id in the two pane UI case.
这种做法就是不论是单页模式
The pattern here is that the detail fragment will always be
还是双页模式  detail fragment都会放在
added to a container called weather_detail_container,
id为weather_detail_container的容器里
both in the two pane, and one pane case.
既然我们更改了容器的id
Since we changed the name of the container,
我们也应该更新一下DetailActivity.java中的代码
we should also update the detail activity.
它只在单页模式下才会用到
This is only used in one pane mode.
在这改一下容器的id
Here's where we change the container name.
在单页模式下  DetailActivity会在该容器内
In the one pane mode the detail activity will add the detail fragment
动态加载出detail fragment
dynamically to this container.
修改完xml布局文件之后  我们应该更新一下MainActivity.java
After we modify the layout we should update the main activity so
让它动态加载DetailFragment
we dynamically add the detail fragment.
在MainActivity.java的onCreate方法中  我们首先检查
In the main activity on create method we check for the presence of the weather
id为weather_detail_container的容器是否存在  来判断当前是否是双页模式
detail container in the layout to know whether this is a two pane UI or not.
我们声明了一个布尔类型的变量mTwoPane保存该判断
We keep track of this information in a Boolean called mTwoPane.
由于mTwoPane属于类的成员变量  所以一定要以m开头命名  切记
Remember that we start with the letter m, because it's a member variable.
比如现在是双页显示  mTwoPane就该是true
In this case, the Boolean should be true.
所以继续往下执行  动态加载出detail fragment
So we go ahead and create a new detail fragment, and
并将其放入weather_detail_container
add it to the weather_detail_container.
我们通过一个fragment事务提交修改
We commit the change by using a fragment transaction,
之前Rado已经介绍过了
which Rado introduced earlier.
另一种情况  若weather_detail_container不存在
Otherwise If the detail container is not present in the layout, then
mTwoPane值为false  意味着目前处在手机的单页模式
the boolean should be false, meaning that this is a one-pane UI for phones.
这种情况下  显示detail fragment内容的工作交由DetailActivity来完成
In this case, the detail activity will handle showing the detail fragment.
注意到  在双页模式下savedInstanceState值为null时
Notice for the two-pane case that we check if the saved instant state
我们才去动态加载detail fragment
bundle is null.
如果savedInstanceState值不为null
If the save instant save bundle is not null,
我们不会再去新创建出来一个  原因如下
then we don't create a new one, and here is the reason why.
在旋转设备之前
Say you want to rotate the device.
app已经是双页显示了
Before the activity and
这时在savedInstanceState已经存放了数据
fragments get torn down, we store information in save state bundles.
改变屏幕方向之后  系统重新载入activity和fragment
Then after the orientation change, the system restores the activity and
会读取savedInstanceState参数中的数据
the fragments, by passing back the same bundle, so
并将显示内容复原到设备旋转之前的样子
that it can be recreated with the same state.
也就是说如果savedInstanceState中有数据
That means if the bundle exists, then we should let the system
我们应该告知系统要复原之前的detail fragment  也就可以跳过这段代码
handle restoring the detail fragment, and we can skip this code.
当detail fragment改为动态加载之后
Once a detail fragment is added dynamically.
给fragment_detail.xml里的控件都加上默认要显示的内容  这对测试有帮助
Make it show some placeholder data just for testing purposes.
接下来我们会深入探究右半部分的逻辑
Later we'll plumb through the right logic, so that it can display the right
它会根据左边所选的日期来显示当天天气的详情
information for the selected date on the left.
修改DetailFragment.java
Modify the detail fragment so
我们需要考虑无数据传进来的情况
that it doesn't expect the incoming intent to have a data URI.
在这种情况下  右边detail fragment部分只会显示
In this case, the detail fragment will just fall back
fragment_detail.xml里各控件的默认内容
to some placeholder data that we have in our XML.
这里intent可能会为空的原因是因为
The reason the intent could be blank is because the detail fragment
DetailFragment现在可以在MainActivity中存在
can now exist within the main activity.
MainActivity在显示时不会事先选择一个日期
And the main activity isn't launched with a URI for
这跟在DetailActivity显示时的情况类似
only one date like the detail activity is normally launched with.
对控件布局优化之后
Once you make the changes for
app就变成了现在这样
the wire frames this is what the app should look like.
这里没有显示天气图标的原因是因为
The reason it doesn't show an icon here is because
我们移走了布局文件里的该ImageView的默认图片
we removed the icon from being hard-coded in the layout.
在之后的视频中  当去动态加载时
But once this data is populated dynamically in a later section,
图标就会出现了
it should show up again.